Nicolas Mavromatis

Data Scientist



PROFILE



(+33) 07 57 87 86 01



mavromatis.nico@gmail.com



Etampes France



French nationality

LANGUAGES

French: Native language English: B2 (TOEIC Score=789)



profil.researchgate



url.linkedin

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming:

Python

Data manipulation:

- Pandas
- Numpy
- Pvspark

Data visualization:

- Matplotlib
- Seaborn

Machine learning:

Scikit-Learn

DeepLearning:

- Keras
- TensorFlow

SOFTWARE

Biological signal analysis:

- Labchart
- Signal
- Spike
- SPM

OBJECTIVE

After several years in the field of neuroscience research, I decided to start a career in data science. Convinced of the relevance of data science in solving complex problems, I would now like to put my experience to good use in solving real-life challenges.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

January 2023 – July 2023

Data Scientist Project – DataScientest Formation

Development of machine learning and deep learning models to classify motor movements from EEG and fNIRS signals

- Data visualization
- Model building and tuning
- Comparison of multiple algorithms (machine learning & deep learning)

2022 – Present (Brétigny-sur-Orge – France)

Postdoctoral researcher

Institut de Recherches Biomédicales des Armées – ECSO unit (Ergonomise Cognitive des Situations Opérérationnelles)

- Modeling fighter pilots' trust in AI
- Measurement of performance in a dynamic situation (flight mission)

2018 -2021 (Quebec-Canada)

Research coordinator

CHU Université Laval Research Center – NOVA Stim lab

- Simultaneous management of several clinical research projects
- Student training and supervision
- Training of clinical staff in neurostimulation

FORMATION

2022-2023

Data Scientist | Remote learning

■ Datascientest.com / Les MINES ParisTech

2013-2017

Ph.D Experimental Medicine

Université Laval, Quebec, Canada

2010-2012

Master's Degree - Integrative and Cognitive Neurosciences

Université Aix-Marseille I, Marseille, France

2010

Bachelor's Degree in biology, Neuroscience speciality

Université Aix-Marseille I, Marseille, France

REFERENCES

Cyril Schneider (NOVA Stim Team Director)

cyril.schneider@rea.ulaval.ca

Thomas Boehler (DataScientest)

thomas@datascientest.com